Guide to the Actors' Fund of America Records WAG.036
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Fundraising Activities, 1886-2002; 183462
  - Subseries V:C: Bread Basket Campaigns, 1938-1980., 183479
    - Road Theatres: Collection Sheets, 1981; 183521 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Sacramento Music Circus, 1965-1980; 183520 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Sebastian Dinner Theater, 1978; 183519 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Shady Grove Music Fair, 1975; 183518 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Sharon Playhouse, 1965-1970, 1978; 183517 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Shubert Theaters: Holiday Matinee Schedules, 1976-1978; 183516 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Simon, Neil (Bread Basket Chairman), 1972-1973; 183515 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Smithville Theatre, 1978; 183514 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Southbury Playhouse, 1966-1980; 183513 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Speeches, 1965-1969, 1973-1976; 183512 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Star Musicals of Flint, Jul 1978; 183511 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Summer Bread Basket, 1966, 1969; 183510 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Summer Bread Basket, 1976-1978; 183509 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Summer Bread Basket, 1979; 183508 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Summer Bread Basket, 1980; 183507 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Summer Bread Basket: Dinner Collections, 1980; 183506 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Summer Bread Basket: Expenses, 1977; 183505 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Summer Bread Basket: Form Letters, 1965-1973; 183504 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Summer Bread Basket: Herald Distribution, undated, 1968; 183503 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Summer Bread Basket: Reports, 1965-1974; 183502 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Summer Bread Basket: Tallies, 1938, 1958-1977; 183501 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Theatre by the Sea, 1977-1978; 183500 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Totem Pole Playhouse, Jul 1978; 183499 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - Town and Country Playhouse, 1978-1979; 183498 (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - Ushers' Union, Information for, undated, 1975; 183497 (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Village Dinner Theater, Jan 1981; 183496 (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Westbury Music Fair, 1975-1979; 183495 (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Westport Country Playhouse, 1970-1971, 1975-1979; 183494 (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Wilbur Theatre, 1978; 183493 (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Williamstown Theater, 1965-1967, 1970-1980; 183492 (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - Winter Bread Basket, 1968-1974; 183491 (Box 26, Folder 52)
    - Winter Bread Basket, 1975-1977; 183490 (Box 26, Folder 53)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Form Letters, 1964-1968; 183489 (Box 26, Folder 54)
    - Winter Bread Basket: New York Theatres, 1966-1975; 183488 (Box 26, Folder 55)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Publicity, 1963; 183487 (Box 26, Folder 56)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Publicity, 1964-1965; 183486 (Box 26, Folder 57)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Road Theatres, 1964-1971; 183485 (Box 26, Folder 58)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Road Theatres, 1972-1977; 183484 (Box 26, Folder 59)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Speakers Assignments, 1965-1974; 183483 (Box 26, Folder 60)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Speakers, 1965-1974; 183482 (Box 26, Folder 61)
    - Winter Bread Basket: Tallies, 1964-1972; 183481 (Box 26, Folder 62)
    - Wolfboro Playhouse, 1979; 183480 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - Subseries V:D: Benefits, Clippings Scrapbooks, 1934-1968., 183463
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, 1934; 183478 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, 1935; 183477 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, 1936; 183476 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, 1937; 183475 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, 1938; 183474 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, Jan 1939-May 1939; 183473 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, Jul 1939-Dec 1939; 183472 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, Jan 1940-Apr 1940; 183471 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, May 1940-Nov 1940; 183470 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, Jan 1940-Jun 1941; 183469 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, Oct 1940-Dec 1941; 183468 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, Jan 1940-Mar 1942; 183467 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, Apr 1940-Nov 1942; 183466 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, 1943; 183465 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Benefits: Clipping Scrapbook, 1961-1968; 183464 (Box 27, Folder 15)
- Series VI: Catholic Actors Guild Records, 1924-1980; 183434
  - Anniversary, 1924; 183461 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Anniversary, 1930; 183460 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary (50th): Plaque Face, 1964; 259649 (Box 28, Folder 2a)
  - Award Presentations, 1970-1980; 183459 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Benefit, 1936; 183458 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Call Board, 1964-1972; 183457 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Call Board, 1973-1976; 183456 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Call Board, 1977; 183455 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Call Board, 1978; 183454 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Call Board, 1979-1980; 183453 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Cardinal Spelliman: To George Buck; St Genesius Medal, 1949; 259647 (Box 28, Folder 9a)
  - Communion Breakfast, 1965; 183452 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Cohan, George M.: Clippings, 1940-1961; 259645 (Box 28, Folder 10A)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1965; 183451 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Dinner-Dance, 1975; 183450 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Dinner-Dance, 1976; 183449 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Dinner-Dance, 1977; 183448 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Dinner-Dance, 1978; 183447 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Dinner-Dance: Archbishop Fulton J. Sheen Tributes, 1977; 183446 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Dinner-Dance: Entertainment, 1975; 183445 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Dinner-Dance: Florence Henderson, 1975; 183444 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Dinner-Dance: Florence Henderson Tributes, 1975; 183443 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Dinner-Dance: Gifts and Prizes, 1977; 183442 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Dinner-Dance: Prizes, 1975; 183441 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Dinner-Dance: Souvenir Signatures, 1975; 183440 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Dinner-Dance: Souvenir Signatures, 1977; 183439 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Executive Board, 1973, 1978-1979; 183438 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1971-1978; 183437 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Finances, 1943, 1967-1979; 183436 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Membership Figures, 1938-1970; 183435 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Most Holy Father (framed and signed by unidentified individual), undated; 452451 (Box 40)
  - Papal Certificate, 1960; 259648 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Smith, Reverand John Talbot: Award from Columbian Assembly of New York, 1909; 452437 (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Series VII: Rathbone Family Papers, 1903-1974; 183409
  - Being and Doing and Character and Conduct, Books with Inscription from Parent, 1906-1907; 183433 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Rathbone, Basil, undated; 183432 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Rathbone, Basil, 1913, 1920-1945; 183431 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Rathbone, Basil, 1950-1967; 183430 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Rathbone, Cynthia (from Basil), undated, 1940-1953; 183429 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Rathbone, Ouida, undated, 1942-1974; 183428 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Rathbone, Ouida (from Basil), undated; 183427 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Rathbone, Ouida (from Basil), 1926-1928, 1941-1967; 183426 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, Rathbone, Ouida: Publishing, 1963-1968, 1971; 183425 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Estate of Basil Rathbone, undated, 1967-1969; 183424 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Family History, undated, 1945; 183423 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Letters from an Uitlanderer, Book Reviews, 1903; 183422 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Literary Material Recorded and Considered, undated; 183421 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Rathbone, Basil: Contracts, 1967-1968; 183420 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Rathbone, Basil: In and Out of Character, Galley Proofs, 1962; 183419 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Rathbone, Basil: In and Out of Character, Page Proofs, 1962; 183418 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: "Cynthia Rathbone Story," Draft, undated; 183417 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: "Happy Weddings," Manuscript, undated; 183416 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: Manuscript (I), undated; 183415 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: Manuscript (II), undated; 183414 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: Manuscript (III), undated; 183413 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: Manuscript (IV), undated; 183412 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: Manuscript (V), undated; 183411 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Rathbone, Ouida: Manuscript (VI), undated; 183410 (Box 29, Folder 13)
- Series VIII: Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers Records, 1959-1980; 183396
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1959-1962; 183408 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1963; 183407 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1964-1966; 183406 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1967; 183405 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1968; 183404 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1969; 183403 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1970; 183402 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1971; 183401 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1972; 183400 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1973; 183399 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter, 1974-1976; 183398 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter, 1977-1980; 183397 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Series IX: Oversize Items, 1891-1965; 183380
  - Actors' Fund: Clippings, 1910-1926; 183395 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Actors' Fund Events (Actors' Fund Home, Anniversaries, Bread Basket Campaigns, and Annual Softball Game): Clippings, 1954-1961; 183394 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Actors' Fund Events (Actors' Fund Home, Anniversaries, Bread Basket Campaigns, and Annual Softball Game): Clippings, Press Releases, and Programs, 1956-1958; 183393 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Actors' Fund Fair: Clippings and Programs (partial) (I), undated, 1892-1917; 183392 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Actors' Fund Fair: Clippings and Programs (partial) (II), undated, 1910-1917; 183391 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Actors' Fund Fair: Clippings and Programs (partial) (III), undated, 1910-1917; 183390 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Actors' Fund Fair: Fair Topics and The Spectator (published for the Fair), 1892-1907; 183389 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Actors' Fund Fair: Friars Epistle (published for the Fair), 1917; 183388 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Actors' Fund Fair: New York Dramatic Mirror: Clippings, 1891-1892; 183387 (Box 32, Folder 1a)
  - Actors' Fund Founding and Actors' Fund Home: Collages, 1900, 1902; 183386 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Actors' Fund Medal, 1970-1976; 452436 (Box 32, Folder 2a)
  - Actors' Fund: Programs (partial), undated, 1915-1917; 183385 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Cohan, George M.: Memorial Resolution, Signed by AF Officers, Dec 1, 1942; 295777 (Box 32, Folder 3a)
  - Drawings (unidentified), undated; 452435 (Box 32, Folder 3b)
  - Grand Opera: Programs (likely donated for Actors' Fund Auctions), undated, 1902-1965; 183384 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - The Morning Telegraph: Portraits of Individuals who Made Contributions to the Actors' Fund Dime Bank, 1918; 452450 (Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - National Players: 40th Annual Tour (signed posters), 1988-1989; 452449 (Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Night of 100 Stars III: Letter to Alexander H. Cohen from Senator Frank Lautenberg, Eclosing Presentation Copy of his Remarks in the Senate, Jun 12, 1990; 294768 (Box 32, Folder 4a)
  - Theater Programs, 1891-1897, 1958; 183383 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Third Subscription Concert, Bath, New Assembly Rooms: Broadside (likely donated for Actors' Fund Auctions), Dec 2, 1901; 183382 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Tomkins, Don: Wildcat Scrapbook: Clippings, 1960; 183381 (Box 32, Folder 7)
- Series X: Scrapbooks and Unprocessed Material, 1875-2014; 183344
  - Subseries X:A: Hardcopy Scrapbooks, 1908-1973., 183361
    - Actors' Fund Benefits Clippings, 1961-1967; 183379 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Actors' Fund General Clippings, 1962-1973; 183378 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Actors' Fund Special Performances Clippings, 1967-1973; 183377 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Obituaries, Vol. I, 1913-May 3, 1918; 183376 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Obituaries, Vol. II, May 8, 1918-Jun 29, 1923; 183375 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Obituaries, Vol. III, Jun 29, 1923-Oct 8, 1927; 183374 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Obituaries, Vol. IV, Oct 19, 1927-Aug 1933; 183373 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Simon, Louis: Includes programs, press clippings, reviews, production photos, and original correspondence relating to theatre productions Simon worked on. Press materials also relate to the theatre scene. Subjects include Max Reinhardt, Lillian Gish, Ethel Barrymore, and picketing WPA personnel cuts. Correspondents include William Hollman, Marion Kohn, and Bide Dudley. Because Simon served as state director of the WPA Federal Theatre of New Jersey, a significant portion of programs, press and photos relate to WPA productions (1936-1937). These include "It Can't Happen Here," "The Trial of Dr. Beck," "The Emperor's New Clothes," "Treasure Island," and "The Adelphi Theatre.", 1924-1940; 183372 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Theater Programs, 1908-1913; 183371 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Theater Programs, 1913-1917; 183370 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Theater Programs, 1916-1919; 183369 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Theater Programs, 1920-1921; 183368 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Theater Programs, 1932-1933; 183367 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Theater Programs (front and back cover of scrapbook), 1932-1933; 183366 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - USO: "Hellz-a-Poppin" Show: Includes journal reflections on travel and happenings behind the scenes of USO tour of army posts, arranged chronologically and by place. Also includes press reviews, and memorabilia such as postcards, travel brochures, and the army publications The Kelly Weekly and Beam: Hondo AAFNS Weekly, a military map of the "Strategic Middle Route" by the Union Pacific Railroad, cast and staff lists and autographs, and pages listing tour statistics. (I), 1942-1943, 1965, 1967; 183365 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - USO: "Hellz-a-Poppin" Show (II), 1942-1943, 1965, 1967; 183364 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - USO: "Hellz-a-Poppin" Show (photocopies of outer scrapbook binder), undated; 183363 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - USO: "Hellz-a-Poppin" Show (original outer binder), undated; 183362 (Box 37)
  - Subseries X:B: Microfilmed Scrapbooks, 1900-1961., 183345
    - Scrapbook 1 (Microfilm), 1900-1902; 183360 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 2 (Microfilm), 1910; 183359 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 3 (Microfilm), 1915-1918; 183358 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 4 (Microfilm), 1916-1918; 183357 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 5 (Microfilm), 1915-1928; 183356 (Box 7822/2)
    - Scrapbook 6 (Microfilm), 1922-1928; 183355 (Reel 7822/2)
    - Scrapbook 7 (Microfilm), 1925-1931; 183354 (Reel 7822/3)
    - Scrapbook 8 (Microfilm), 1926-1927; 183353 (Reel 7822/3)
    - Scrapbook 9 (Microfilm), 1941-1953; 183352 (Reel 7822/3)
    - Scrapbook 10 (Microfilm), 1942; 183351 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 11 (Microfilm), 1943-1947; 183350 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 12 (Microfilm), 1947-1953; 183349 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 13 (Microfilm), 1953-1957; 183348 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 14 (Microfilm), 1954-1958; 183347 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 15 (Microfilm), 1957-1961; 183346 (Reel 7822/4)
  - Subseries X:C: Unprocessed Material, 1875-2014., 295776
    - Unprocessed Material, 2000s; 374457 (Box 33)
    - Unprocessed Material, 2000s; 374458 (Box 38)
    - George M. Cohan Dinner Phonograph Records (Fragile), 1938; 374459 (Box 39)
    - Arrangements of Funerals and Burials for Actor's Fund Members, undated; 553015 (Box 49)
    - Annual Report Research Materials, circa 1990-1999; 553016 (Box 50)
    - Development Files, 1996; 553017 (Box 51)
    - Programs, Photographs and DVDs of Events and Benefits; Brochures; Miscellaneous Historical Materials, 1875-2014; 585781 (Box 52)
    - Oversized Historical Materials, 1900s-1960s; 585785 (Box MSOS006)
      Scope and Content Note
      Includes early photographs of Joe Smith and Charles Dale, as well as a 1920s photograph of the Board of Trustees for The Actors Fund.
- Series XI: Aldrich Family Papers, circa 1850-1940; 553009
  - Scrapbooks, Photographs, Programs, and Publicity Materials, circa 1850-1940; 553010 (Box 41)
  - Scrapbooks, circa 1850-1940; 553011 (Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46)
  - Oversize Photographs, circa 1850-1940; 553012 (Box 47)
  - Actors' Fund Scrapbooks, circa 1850-1940; 553013 (Box 48)
- Series XII: Archived Website, Mar 29, 2009-ongoing; 544993
  The Actors Fund, a nonprofit human services organization founded in 1882, serves professionals in film, theater, television, music, opera, and dance through programs that address their professional needs. The Fund serves more than 12,000 performing arts and entertainment professionals across the country every year, and reaches hundreds of thousand through the Fund's online resources. The Fund operates as a safety net, to provide programs and services, including comprehensive social services, health services, supportive and affordable housing, employment and training services, and skilled nursing and assisted living care for performing arts and entertainment professionals in need. The website contains information on their services and programs, tickets to upcoming performances and events, and education and workshops.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.